So with your business side of things,
do you have an email list?
No. Do you know what?
I started watching your videos on this
stuff because it
wasn't the
first time that I'd looked at the email
marketing bits and pieces, and I started
watching your videos on it. I mean,
one of them was a fucking hour, so I
was trying
to put it on fast-forward. I was like,
"Fucking hell,
can't he just tell me what I
need to do?" And you're like...
And I went to click on the links to sign
up, I was
like, "Fuck." Yeah,
so I really think it's a really good
thing.
I do. I actually,
when I saw one of your most recent posts,
I thought, I'm going to
talk to him about this-
Yeah
... when I see him in person. So you make,
and to anyone listening, feel free, if
you're just a rugby fan, this could help.
Yeah.
Try the new flavor.
Yeah, well, I've tried three of them.
Oh my God, I'm so focused.
Let me know what you think of this one.
Fine. This is so nice.
[chuckles] But you know you've seen that
Role Models, when they keep drinking
that Minotaur, and they're pissing green
stuff. [chuckles] Yeah.
It's going to be you.
Hmm.
So-
Oh, wow
... see that one,
the blue one's the one I drink the most.
The white one used to be our OG.
The strawberry lemonade is great, but I
don't know if I could do 12 in a row.
No, I wouldn't, yeah.
I don't think you want to medically-
Not today
... drink 12 in a row anyway, yeah.
So with the...
You sell sometimes direct on social media.
Yeah.
And I don't like
that because basically everything you post
on social media is
scored on how people react to it. Now,
out of all the Haskell fans, let's say 2%
of them are appropriate for the training.
That means 98% of people aren't going to
vibe with it, no matter how much-
Yeah
... they love you and the brand.
Which means that if the social media
platform, Instagram, Facebook, whatever,
sees 98% of people are not vibing, it's
not going to push it.
Yeah.
So the asset that you need to get in front
of people is going to be hindered
through the way you're promoting it.
Yeah.
Now,
I've always thought,
imagine the amount of stories
that Hask has in his head-
Yeah
... from back in the day, whatever.
He could share those with his audience
because I reckon maybe 35% of your
audience
would love-
Yeah
...
to have a little distraction maybe once a
week where they're having a shit at
work on the toilet, and it's you,
whether it's the Regan story,
whether it's this-
Yeah
... whether it's that, whatever,
then they can have a perfect distraction
from it.
Then at the end of the email, you say,
"If you fat click here, if you've got a
social event, click here,"
and you have your products listed at the
bottom.
Yeah.
Because then if it's 2% of your audience
that are interested in booze, cool, but
then I would say
that maybe 35% of them will hear from you
weekly with an email.
10% of those could be appropriate for the
ecosystem-
Yeah
... of Hask products. And even
if they're not wanting to buy a bottle of
booze,
even if they're not wanting coaching at
the bottom, "Hey, listen to this song."
Yeah.
"Add this to your playlist." Because
you're now building an ecosystem,
like a suite
of products.
You need to be able to connect them from
socials to that.
Yeah.
So whether it's
special events,
you could also start bringing into the mix
your DJing and booze.
Yeah.
You could work with a PR company
and be like, "Right,
we're going to do a charity
dinner.
There's going to be a bottle on each
table."
Yeah.
"There's going to be a little set
that I do in the evenings." And then
when you do
big galas and events or whatever,
all of their data goes on Dreamcast.
Yeah.
So the following week,
you just go back into your Hask stories
or whatever it is.
Do you use Mailchimp and stuff like that?
Is that what you're talking about?
Because I-
In my own personal opinion,
Mailchimp's the worst of all of them.
Oh, really?
Mm.
What is the best one I should-
What should I get involved in?
Well, there's a lot. One that I use,
I get a bit of
flak for. I like the one
that I started using in 2014.
It's called AWeber,
and it's the most basic.
It's retard proof.
Right.
But there are loads I can send you
offline.
And in essence, what we need to create
is just a page where
occasionally you say to people,
"Want to hear from me? Click here.
Want to know about events?
Click here." You could even say to people,
"I'm about to
throw
Jason Robinson under the bus.
I'll send this email in 12 hours."
And then people
sign up because through like FOMO
or whatever it is.
Yeah.
Then everything you do promotionally gets
added to that.
Let's say you're going to...
Or you might even say you might auction
off an event, or you might do something,
or
you could be like, "Hey guys,
join my email list,
and in the next 24 hours,
I'm going to pick someone at random.
I'm going to drive to their house
and give them a bottle of Black Eye."
Yeah.
You know, whatever it is.
Because that 1,000 emails over the course
of the next four months could be
commercially worth a lot to you.
Then anything you do as an event,
you might even
say,
there might be a speaking event,
and they might say, "Oh, this
is our budget." You
go, "It's a little bit light, but
if you share with me all the data from the
event,
I'll come do it for that."
Yeah.
So then you want to build like an asset of
that.
So what people don't realize a lot is
when Chris and I launched, we had
hundreds of thousands of people we could
go to in a direct channel, and that
really to me is the meta of marketing,
where if you have a good day or a bad day,
that's still something you can
communicate.
Yeah. I think that's great.
And do you know what?
I literally was thinking,
I think I just haven't been doing that,
and I was like,
that's a spot on idea because we
were actually talking about
that. I mean, I-
And good about the rugby as well.
Yeah.
You run events-
I know
... you be like, "Hey guys,
if you want to get the episodes two days
early, sign
up."
Because basically from the
mail clients where you create the link to
get people to sign up, and they
automatically download into that,
whatever software you choose to, AWeb or
whatever.
And you could also automate it where
instead,
rather than having to turn up weekly,
weekly, weekly, weekly,
you can pre-write 30 emails of your best
30 stories.
They sign up, email day one,
wait 24 hours, email two, email three.
So they feel like they've got an email
from you every day for a month.
Yeah.
So then you'd be walking down the street
today, someone will fist bump you and go,
"Mate, today's email was class."
And you haven't written one in a year.
Yeah.
And the reason for this as well
is being a high-energy person
such as yourself,
got a lot of stuff to do, whatever.
Some days when you don't want to be James
Haskell-
Yeah
... you can just write an email.
Yeah.
And that to me is great.
So this week I'm obviously filming lots of
pods, whatever.
If someone was to say, "Oh,
can we do this?" I'd go, "Mate,
I'd rather wank
off a stranger."
Yeah.
But [chuckles] you could go into-
Stranger. [chuckles]
You could go into like introverted space-
Yeah
...
and just in 20 minutes write a little
email, send it, and you can have a
meaningful amount of people get that.
Do you,
again, off the top of line,
but do you send images with the text
and just then make
it look smart?
You never like embed videos?
Just text.
Just text?
Just text,
because I want it to feel like I'm
dropping my mate a message.
Like imagine if after-
You don't design like a whole page thing
with like graphics and bits of a
newsletter? No, just emails?
Yeah, I just put text.
I center align it because I find it easier
to read because
I'm a bit-
Center what?
Center align.
Oh, yeah. I get you.
It's how I write by email. And then,
it's conversational,
and then I'll even put
unfunny jokes, then type,
"Ha ha?" Question mark,
and move to the next bit.
Yeah, fine.
And imagine like, after today,
maybe even after today, I was to send you
like a little WhatsApp, "Hey mate,
thanks for coming on today.
Really appreciate it.
Thank you so much for this.
You made me really think about this.
If you need anything,
don't feel to get in touch." I wouldn't
put like an image,
"Hey,
here's a picture of us from earlier."
Yeah. I get you.
Or like James Smith Media.
Yeah. Well, that's what I... Again,
because when you're talking,
my mind's like,
"This is something I haven't been doing.
What have I been doing?
Why have I not been doing this?"
Literally,
I'm going to go here this afternoon and
go and start doing it. But I'm just-
And again,
like imagine you have your plate on your
wrist.
Yeah.
You could be like
One thing's crossed my mind.
Wanking will never be the same again.
Yeah.
And you know,
so today I'm going to have to see
if I can wank left-handed.
For you,
you're just going to have to buy a bottle
of Black Eye.
Yeah. Fine.
Which one's worse? Don't know.
See you tomorrow.
Yeah.
And you know you're saying about having
humor and
comedy to what you do,
you will actually find material writing.
You'll also have material you can put in
there.
Yeah.
Also,
the fact if you become active in a written
format, and once you've written
that marketing email,
chuck it on LinkedIn, chuck it on Twitter.
Yeah. Well,
I love writing because I wrote my books.
I love Touch Type,
and it's my favorite escape.
I'm literally writing a fiction book at
the moment. I love that kind of stuff.
So for me, that's like a hobby.
I think we're moving back to X have just
added articles, but so have LinkedIn.
Yeah.
So if you go through Twitter,
now you'll see there are articles
that take you to a
bigger page.
Yeah.
I think that we've gone through a phase of
people being like hyper-edited,
short reels, whatever.
Yeah.
But then on the other side,
the reason some people might really enjoy
listening to
you today on the pod
is to get a long-form hat.
Yeah.
That could even be what it's called.
Just to get a little bit of...
Because you have to be a certain persona
online.
It gives you permission to be whoever you
want.
And imagine you go through a big life
trauma, trauma, or
whatever. Sometimes,
I missed a flight for the first time last
week, and it cost me £4,000 to
change. And I was like,
"Just going to make an email."
Yeah.
And at the bottom of it, I was like,
"If you want a worse day than me,
don't join
my program."
Yeah.
But the fitness thing as well, let's say,
you have someone go through a program and
get a good testimonial.
Yeah.
If you put it on socials, unfortunately,
no one cares.
Yeah.
But if you put it in your email list,
still a lot of people don't care,
but a lot more people do-
Yeah
... because they're invested.
Yeah. Fine. Look, [scoffs]
let's wrap this up so I can go off
and start sending emails.
I need to do that because I just needed to
find the mail client that
was simple that I could do,
because I obviously got the music stuff,
so I'd have to
have different streams.
I'd have James Haskell stuff.
You'd have the health and fitness stuff,
and then you'd have the Haskell music
stuff, which will be different.
But it's which best client,
but I went for Aweb.
And at the end, even
if you're not interested in buying
anything-
Here's my... Yeah
... listen to my song, you cunt.
Yeah. [both laughing]
Whenever you have a new track,
you give it to the list first.
Whenever you have an idea,
you hash it to those guys first.
That's great.
But you reckon Aweb's for it?
You're going to have a marketing person
that's over your websites or whatever.
Run it past them because they might have a
client.
Like Klaviyo is probably the best,
but Klaviyo can be quite complex.
But the beautiful thing about that
is people
can come from different places,
and you can apply tags to them.
So you might have a UK subset.
Right.
So if you've got people in America
or Australia, whatever, you can segment
them in different ways.
Okay.
You can also have it where
if some people buy,
let's say they go through-
Yeah
... to the checkout and buy,
you can then add them to another
follow-up.
It's been 30 days since you bought.
Hopefully, you've drunk it by now.
Do you want to buy more?
Fine. All right. Okay. I'm on it.
So we, for Neutonic, we have people
that buy, people that don't buy,
abandon cart.
For my fitness app, we have the main list.
Yeah.
People that trialed and never bought.
Then people that have bought
and then haven't bought anymore.
Yeah.
And then you can have different messages
to go to different people.
But whenever I see you promoting on
socials-
Yeah
...
I'm just thinking there's a funnel
missing.
There is.
There is a massive funnel missing